난 우주에서 태어났다
Clarke, voice-over: I was born in space.
내 얼굴에 비치는 햇살을
느껴본 적이 없었다
I've never felt the sun on my face
진짜 공기를 숨쉬거나
물 위에 떠본 적도 없었다
or breathed real air
or floated in the water.
우리들 중 아무도
None of us have. For 3 generations,
3세대 동안 Ark가
인류를 지켜줬지만
The Ark has kept what's
left of the human race alive,
지금은 죽어가고 있다
but now our home is dying, and we
우린 인류의 마지막 희망이다
are the last hope of mankind.
100명의 재소자들은 극단적인 임무로
지구로 보내졌다
100 prisoners sent on a
desperate mission to the ground.
개개인들은 법을 어겼기에
이곳에 왔다
Each of us is here
because we broke the law.
지구에선
법이 존재하지 않는다
On the ground, there is no law.
우리가 할 일은
살아남으면서
All we have to do is survive.
지구의 시험대에
오를 것이다
But we will be tested,
by the earth, by the secrets it hides,
그리고 무엇보다도
서로의 비밀을 감추면서
and most of all, by each other.
The 100 지난 이야기
Woman, voice-over:
Previously on "The 100"...
Ark는 죽어가고 있어, 레이븐
The Ark is dying, Raven.
지구에서 생존 여부를
증명해야 해
I have to prove that earth is survivable.
네가 9일 안에
준비해야
We have 9 days to get this ready
내가 내려갈 수 있어
so I can survive a drop.
내 아빠가 처형당할 때
살려달라 애걸했지
You know, my father, he begged for mercy
when your father floated him.
이건 내 아빠 몫이야
This is for my father.
Uhh! Uhh! Uhh!
너 샤를로트지, 응?
You're Charlotte, right?
무서운 게
당연해
It's ok to be scared.
얘기하고 싶니?
Do you want to talk about it?
제 부모님이었어요
우주로 처형됐어요
It's my parents. They were floated
그리고 꿈에 보여요
and I see it in my dreams.
- 안 돼!
- 일어나, 샤를로트
No! Wake up, Charlotte.
자주 이러니?
Does it happen often?
[Sigh]
악령을 죽이면
Slay your demons, kid.
푹 잘 수 있을 거야
Then you'll be able to sleep.
- synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.addic7ed.com -
우리말 옮긴이 : BaeZZi
여기 혼자 있으면 안 돼
You shouldn't be out here alone.
내가 지면인이었으면?
What if I was a grounder?
바깥쪽 벽에서
웰스가 죽었어
They got Wells just outside the wall.
스스로 숲속을 탐험하면서
밤을 새운 애한테 말해
Says the guy who just spent another night
exploring the woods all by himself.
난 앞뒤를 가리지 않아
무책임하고
But I'm reckless. And irresponsible.
보여줄 게 있어
I got you something.
- 이건 어디서 났어?
- Ark 물품 창고에서
Where did you get this?
The art supply store.
우리가 어렸을 때...
I know when we were kids...
웰스는 늘 내게
잉크와 목탄을 줘서
Wells was always giving me ink, charcoal,
난 아무거나
그릴 수 있었어
just anything I could draw with, really.
내게 줄려고 자기 물건을
교환한 걸 후에 알게 됐어
I found out later that he was trading
his own stuff to give it to me.
걔는 내가 아는 걸
원치도 않았었어
He didn't want me to know that, either.
내가 자기를 미워하도록 해줘서
난 엄마를 미워할 수가 없었어
He let me hate him
so that I wouldn't hate my mother.
알아
I know.
엄마가 아빠를 죽였어
My mother killed my father.
내가 뭐라도
해 줄 수 있으면 좋겠어
Just wish there was something I could do.
엄마에게 전하면
가슴이 미어질...
To tell her I know.
Make her feel what I'm...
어딜 갈려고?
Where are you going?
엄마도 느끼게 해야지
To make her feel it.
[Beeping]
안 돼!
안 돼
No! No.
안 돼, 빌어먹을
안 돼
No. Hell no. No.
전송 종결
아니, 이건 옳지 않아
No. Th... this isn't right.
애비
Abby.
안 돼
No.
애비
Abby.
이건 확실치 않아
Ok. It's not conclusive.
딸애 팔찌 신호가
꺼졌다 해도
Just because her wristband went out
죽은 건 아냐...
doesn't mean... ok.
처음으로 일주일 이상
전송이 종결됐어
It's the first terminated
signal in over a week.
지구 기후를 안정시킬 게
있다고 볼 수 있어
We can still assume that
things are stabilizing on earth.
그걸 추정해야 돼
We should assume that.
지난 이틀 동안 클라크의
생명 신호를 분석해 줘
I need an analysis of Clarke's
vital signs for the past two days.
- 애비...
- 내가 돌아올 때 준비시켜 놔
- Abby...
- Just have it ready for me
when I get back.
떼어냈어
Yes! I did it.
아직 작동 돼
It's still operational.
왜? 몬티는 팔찌가
필요했잖아
What? Monty needed a working wristband.
넌 네 엄마에게
벌 주고자 했고
And you needed to punish your mother.
공기가 바닥날 거야
그들 도움이 필요해
Look, they're running out of air,
and we need their help.
엄만 내가 한시적으로
죽었다고 생각할 거야
My mother thinking I'm
dead is only temporary.
내가 드랍십 중앙 컴퓨터에
연결을 못하는 게 아니라면
Not if I can't patch it through
the dropship mainframe.
할 순 있어
I can do it.
해질녘까지 Ark와
교신할 거야
We'll be talking to The Ark by nightfall.
[Indistinct chatter]
이 구역은 내일까지
끝내야 해
This section should be
finished by tomorrow.
Uhh.
야!
Hey!
지면인들이 마냥
기다릴 것 같냐고
You think the grounders
are just gonna sit around
벽을 끝마칠 동안?
and wait for us to finish the wall?
널 저기 꼬마 여자애랑
교체하는 게 낫겠어?
Maybe we should let the little girl
do the lifting for you, huh?
물 좀 먹으면
괜찮을 거야
I just need some water,
ok? Then I'll be fine.
머피, 물 좀 갖다줘
Murphy, get this guy some water.
네가 이거 할래?
Hey, you got this?
농담이야
I'm just kidding.
[Zip]
[Urinating]
대체 뭐가 문제야, 머피?
Uhh! What the hell is
wrong with you, Murphy?
네 꼬라지를 봐!
Look at you!
물 마시고
쉬고 싶다면서
You wanted a water break.
다시 일이나 해
Get back to work.
[Indistinct chatter]
거의 다 왔어
Look, we're already there.
몇 발짝만 가면 돼?
Just a few steps, ok?
한 번에 한 걸음씩 와
One foot in front of the other.
왜 그래?
Hey. What's wrong?
응? 별거 아냐
괜찮아
Hmm? Oh, nothing. I'm good.
제스퍼, 일주일이나 됐잖아?
Jasper, it's been a week, ok?
넌 죽다 살아났으니
You've been given a second chance.
잘 활용해야지
You gotta use it. Aah!
옥타비아?
Octavia?
옥타비아!
옥타비아, 괜찮아?
Octavia! Octavia, are you ok?
Aah!
바보새끼!
Hey, jerk!
여기서 나가자
Get the hell out of here.
제스퍼, 어서
Jasper, come on.
여긴 두려워할 건 없어
There's nothing to be afraid of.
Uhh.
애비 의원
Councillor.
케인 의원
메카 정거장에
가는 길이야?
Are you headed to Mecha Station?
네, 그럼요
Yes, as a matter of fact, I am.
지난 주 9번이나
아래에 내려갔잖아
You've been down there
9 times in the past week.
내가 인지해야할
만한 게 있나?
Is there something I
should be made aware of?
날 염탐하나요?
Are you tracking me, Kane?
난 모두를 염탐해, 애비
I'm tracking everybody, Abby.
같이 가도 괜찮지?
Mind if I join you?
문제될 건 없죠
예방 주사는 맞아야죠
Not at all. But you're gonna
have to be inoculated.
예방 접종?
Inoculated?
지난 주 수리공이
패혈증에 감염됐어요
A mechanic came down with strep last week.
She's fine now, but I'm still
지금은 괜찮은데
지금도 박테리아 수위를
확인하고 있어요
checking the bacterial
levels in the station.
또 다른 발병은
원치 않아요
We don't want another outbreak.
- 가는 길에 병실에 들르죠
- 괜찮아
We can stop by sick bay on the way.
That's all right.
딴지 걸고 싶진 않아
I don't want to slow you down.
그냥...계속 알려주기나 해
Just... keep me informed.
물론이죠
Absolutely.
[Whirring]
언제쯤 준비시킬 수 있어?
How soon can you get
this thing ready to drop?
지금도 압력 조절기를 조립하는데
부품들을 모으고 있어요
I'm still scraping up parts
to fabricate a pressure regulator.
우리 2일 남았죠?
We got two more days, right?
그 부품 없이
발사할 수 있지?
Can we launch without that part?
가능한 데, 땅에 닿기도 전에
죽을 거예요
We could launch, but we'll be dead
before we get to the ground.
개죽음으로요
And I mean bad dead.
폐가 파열되고
뇌에는 기포로요
Ruptured lungs,
air bubbles in the brain.
그 부품이 필요해요
We need that part.
뭐가 잘못됐나요?
상황이 달라졌나요?
Why? What's wrong? Did something change?
클라크의 팔찌 신호가
꺼졌어
Clarke's wristband signal went out.
헌데 그건 아무 의미가
없잖아요?
Yeah, but that doesn't
mean anything, right?
다른 애들처럼
팔찌를 떼어냈잖아요
She took it off like the rest of them.
좋아요
Ok.
압력 조절기를 완성하죠
오늘요
I can get a pressure regulator. Today.
어떻게?
How?
모르시는 게 약이에요
The less you know, the better.
이 칼은 드랍십의 금속으로
만들어진 거야
This knife was made of
metal from the dropship.
그게 무슨 소리야?
What do you mean?
그 밖의 누가 알고 있어?
Who else knows about this?
없어, 바로 가져온 거야
No one. We brought it straight here.
클라크?
Clarke?
지면인들이 웰스를
죽인 게 아냐
It means the grounders didn't kill Wells.
우리들 중 한 명이야
It was one of us.
그럼 이 캠프 안에
살인자가 있어?
So, there's a murderer in the camp?
한 명 이상의 살인자들이
이 캠프 안에 있어
There's more than one
murderer in this camp.
놀랄 일도 아냐
비밀로 해
This isn't news. We need to keep it quiet.
저리 비켜, 벨라미
Get out of my way, Bellamy.
현명해져야지
Be smart about this.
우리가 이뤄낸 걸 봐...
Look at what we've achieved...
벽, 순찰
the wall, the patrols.
좋든 싫든
지면인들이 웰스를
Like it or not, thinking the grounders
죽였다고 생각하면
우리에겐 이점이야
killed Wells is good for us.
너에게 이점이겠지
Oh, good for you, you mean.
애들이 두려워하는 걸
감추면 널 위해 일할까?
What... keep people afraid
and they'll work for you?
- 그런 거야?
- 응, 바로 그거야
- Is that it?
- Yeah, that's it.
하지만 모두에게
이점이야
But it's good for all of us.
지면인들의 두려움이
저 벽을 만들었잖아
Fear of the grounders
is building that wall.
게다가 네가 걸어나가서
살인자 나오라고 물어보면?
And besides, what are you gonna do...
just walk out there and ask
the killer to step forward?
넌 그게 누구 칼인지도
모르잖아
You don't even know whose knife that is.
오, 그래?
Oh, really?
J.M. 존 머피
J.M. John Murphy.
애들은 알 권리가 있어
The people have a right to know.
이 구역 마칠 때까지
물은 없어!
No water till this section is up!
뭐? 뭘 째려보는데?
What? What are you starting at, huh?
이 개자식아!
You son of a bitch!
갑자기 왜 이래?
What's your problem?
이거 알아보겠지?
Recognize this?
내 칼이야
어디서 찾았어?
It's my knife. Where'd you find it?
네가 웰스를 죽인 후
버렸던 곳에서
Where you dropped it
after you killed Wells.
내가 어디서 뭘?
Where I what?
지면인들이 웰스를 죽였어
난 아냐
The grounders killed Wells, not me.
네가 죽였잖아
I know what you did,
- 대가를 치뤄야지
- 그래?
and you're gonna pay for it.
Really?
벨라미, 이런 헛소리
정말 믿는 거야?
Bellamy, you really believe this crap?
걔를 죽인다고 협박했잖아
우리 다 들었어
You threatened to kill
him. We all heard you.
넌 웰스를 미워했어
You hated Wells.
많은 애들이
웰스를 싫어했어
Plenty of people hated Wells.
걔 아빤 우릴 가둔
의장이었어
His father was the
chancellor that locked us up.
근데 걔와 싸울 때
칼을 가진 건 너 뿐이었어
Yeah, but you're the only one who
got in a knife fight with him.
맞아, 하지만
난 안 죽였어
Yeah, I didn't kill him then, either.
제스퍼도 죽이려 했잖아
Tried to kill Jasper, too.
참 어저구니가 없네
Come on. This is ridiculous.
너에게 대답하지 않겠어
어느 누구에게도
I don't have to answer to you.
I don't have to answer to anyone.
뭐라구?
Come again?
벨라미, 말하건대
Bellamy, look, I'm telling you, man.
내가 하지 않았어
I didn't do this.
네 칼과 걔의 손가락을
발견했어
They found his fingers on
the ground with your knife.
이런 게 우리가 원한
공통체였어?
Is this the kind of society that we want?
규칙은 없다고
네가 말했잖아
You say there should be no rules.
그 말은 죄값 없이
서로 죽일 수 있단 소리잖아
Does that mean that we can kill each other
without... without punishment?
이미 말했잖아
난 아무도 안 죽였어
I already told you. I didn't kill anyone.
처형시켜
Man: I say we float him.
- 맞아
Several voices: Yeah.
내 말은 그게 아냐
That's not what I'm saying.
왜 아냐?
쟤는 처형당해도 싸
Why not? He deserves to float.
이건 정의야
Same man: It's justice.
복수는 정의가 아냐
Revenge isn't justice.
이건 정의야
처형 해!
It's justice. Float him!
- 처형 해!
[Crowd chanting "float him"]
안 돼!
떼어 내!
No! Get off him!
[Crowd shouting indistinctly]
떠어 내!
Man: Get off of him!
보내줘!
Let him go!
이러면 안 돼!
Clarke: You can't do this!
저리 비켜
Get off me.
안 돼!
Clarke: No!
네가 멈출 수 있잖아!
You can stop this!
네 말을 들을 거야!
They'll listen to you!
벨라미! 네가 처형 해
Bellamy! You should do it.
벨라미!
Bel-la-my!
- 벨라미!
[Crowd chanting "Bellamy"]
난 숲 속에서 너랑 아톰을 봤어
넌 살인자가 아냐
I saw you in the woods with Atom.
I know you're not a killer.
벨라미, 이러면 안 돼...
Bellamy, don't do this. Don't...
하지 마, 벨라미
Don't. Bellamy.
- 벨라미!
[Crowd continues chanting "Bellamy"]
너 이러면 안 돼, 벨라미
Clarke: You can't do this, Bellamy.
[Muffled speech]
[Crowd cheering]
안 돼, 벨라미
안 돼!
No, Bellamy, no!
이건 네 탓이야, 공주님
This is on you, princess.
네가 입을 다물고
있었어야지
You should've kept your mouth shut.
대체 무슨 짓이야?
Finn: What the hell are you doing?
줄을 짤라!
샤를로트
Cut him down! Charlotte,
내려주라고!
줄을 짤라!
get out of here now! Cut him down!
비켜
Get out of my way.
멈춰요!
Stop! Ok?
머피가 웰스를
안 죽였어요!
Murphy didn't kill Wells!
- 내가 했어요!
- 맙소사
- I did!
- Oh, my God.
Uhh!
아직 식사 시간 아냐
It's not meal time yet.
안 배고파
I'm not hungry.
뭘 바꾸러 왔어
I'm here to trade.
내게 잘못 왔다고
얘기하기 전에
Before you tell me I'm in the wrong place,
나이젤에게 작은 새가
왔다고 해요
just let Nygel know it's her little bird.
이런, 이런, 이런
Nygel: Well, well, well.
이게 얼마 만이야, 작은 새?
How long has it been, little bird?
압력 조절기가 필요해요
I need a pressure regulator.
왜?
What for?
압력을 조절할려고요
Regulating pressure.
그거 좋지
That's good.
네게서 네 엄마의 유머가
나오는구나
I see you got your mom's sense of humor.
원하는 게 뭐예요?
What do you want for it?
더이상 기계 부품은
취급 안 해
Oh, I don't move machine parts anymore.
너무 위험해
It's too dangerous.
다른 사람들처럼 허브와
밀주로 하는 건 어떠니?
How about settling for some
herb and moonshine like everybody else?
세상 물정 모르는 사람에게
써먹으세요
Save the act for someone
who doesn't know better.
뭘 구해줄 수 있는지
얘기나 하세요
Just tell me what it's gonna take.
전기 수장에게
은혜를 입었는데
I owe a favor to the chief of electrical,
그는 너 같이 터프하고
예쁜 여자들을 좋아하지
and he's got a thing for
tough, pretty girls like you.
농담이시죠, 네?
You're joking, right?
난 사업에 관해선
농담 안 해, 레이븐
I never joke about business, Raven.
케인이 내 행동을
전부 감시하니
Kane's watching my every move,
내가 구해다 주면
so, if I'm gonna do this,
내 노력에 값어치 있는
일을 해줘야지
you're gonna need to
make it worth my while.
전기 수장과
잠자리를 가지라고요?
By screwing the chief of electrical?
난 못해요
I can't do that.
그럼 넌 압력 조절기가
궁할 정도는 아닌가 보구나
Then I guess you don't need to
regulate pressure as badly
as you thought you did.
뒈져 버려요, 나이젤
Go float yourself, Nygel.
네 엄마는 그 거래를
받아들였을 거야
You know, your mother
would've taken that deal.
사실은 했었지
수도 없이
In fact, she did. Many times.
그런 식으로 내 엄마에 대해
지껄이지 마!
Don't you dare talk
about my mother that way!
- 아직 어려
- 아니! 당신을 죽여버릴 거야!
- Little girl.
- No! I'll float you, Nygel!
저리 치워!
Get off me!
안녕, 작은 새!
Bye, little bird!
꼬마 애 내보내, 벨라미!
Bring out the girl, Bellamy!
- 왜 그랬니, 샤를로트?
- 난 악령을 죽인 것 뿐이에요
Bellamy: Why, Charlotte?
I was just trying to slay my demons,
오빠가 그랬잖아요
like you told me.
대체 무슨 소리야?
What the hell is she talking about?
날 오해한 거야
She misunderstood me.
샤를로트, 내 말은 그게 아냐
Charlotte, that is not what I meant.
꼬마 애 내보내!
Murphy: Bring the girl out now!
날 해치지 못하게 해요
Please don't let them hurt me.
기발한 생각이 있으면
어서 말해
If you guys have any
bright ideas, speak up.
이젠 입 다무네
Now you stay quiet.
- 쟤들은 네 부하야
- 내 잘못 아냐
Those are your boys out there.
This is not my fault.
쟤가 내 말을 들었으면
쟤들은 벽 짓고 있었을 거야
If she had listened to me, those idiots
would still be building the wall.
공동체를 만들고 싶어, 공주님?
Murphy: You want to
build a society, princess?
공동체를 만들자고
여자 애 내보내
Let's build a society. Bring her out.
안 돼요!
제발, 벨라미
No! Please, Bellamy.
샤를로트, 괜찮을 거야
Charlotte, hey, it's gonna be ok.
쟤들과 같이 있어
Just stay with them.
이런, 이런, 이런
우리와 합류하기로 했군
Well, well, well. Look
who decided to join us.
고만 지껄이고
물러서
Dial it down and back off.
왜? 날 매달아 둘려고?
Or what? What are you
gonna do about me? Hang me?
난 애들이 원했던 걸
줬을 뿐이야
I was just giving the
people what they wanted.
그래, 좋은 생각이야
Yeah. Yeah, that's a good idea.
지금 그걸 하는 게 어때?
Why don't we do that right now?
목 매달린 진짜 살인자를
보고 싶은 사람?
So, who here wants to see
the real murderer hung up?
찬성하는 사람?
All in favor?
좋아
I see.
그럼 아무 이유 없이
날 매달은 건 괜찮고
So, it's ok to string me up for nothing,
저 꼬마 년이 자백했으니
그냥 풀어주겠다?
but when this little bitch confesses,
you all let her walk?
겁쟁이들!
너희 다 겁쟁이들이야!
Cowards! All of you are cowards!
야, 머피!
머피
Hey, Murphy! Murphy.
끝났어
It's over.
명령대로 하죠, 보스
Whatever you say, boss.
개자식!
Octavia: Son of a bitch! Hey!
꼬마 년 잡아
Come on. Let's get the girl.
샤를로트!
Charlotte!
샤를로트, 내 말 들리잖아!
Charlotte, I know you can hear me!
널 찾으면
대가를 치룰 줄 알아!
And when I find you, you are gonna pay!
[Baby crying]
[Coughing]
따라 와
Come on.
곧 돌아올게
I'll be right back.
- 밖에 있는 사람들은요?
- 산소 결핍증
All those people out there?
Oxygen deprivation.
단지 시작일 뿐이야
여긴 왜 왔어?
It's just the beginning. Why are you here?
망했어요
그 부품 못 구해요
I messed up. I can't get the part.
나이젤이 저보고...
Nygel wants me to...
- 나이젤에게 갔어?
- 네
You went to Nygel?
Yeah.
케인이 수년간
그녀를 감시했어
Kane's been trying to get her for years.
널 본 사람은?
Did anybody see you?
모르겠어요
I don't know.
박사님, 진심으로 말하는데
No. Abby, I'm trying to tell you.
오늘 발사 못해요
We can't launch today.
나이젤이 그 부품을
가지고 있긴 해?
Are you sure Nygel has the part?
- 가지고 있어요
- 좋아, 내가 처리하지
- She can get one, yeah.
- Ok. I'll take care of it.
어쩌실려고요?
What are you gonna do?
모르는 게 약이야
The less you know, the better.
안녕하세요
닥터 그리핀
Hello, Dr. Griffin.
나이젤
Nygel.
모르핀이군요
원하는 게 뭐예요?
Morphine. What do you want for it?
압력 조절기요
Pressure regulator.
제가 레이븐을
과소 평가했군요
I underestimated Raven.
어떻게 그런 여자 애가
연줄이 좋은 후원자가 있을까요?
How does a girl like that get
such a well-connected benefactor?
결정하는 데
3초 주겠어요
You have 3 seconds to decide.
거래 할 거요
말 거요?
Do we have a deal or not?
주목하세요
Woman on P.A.: Attention. The mess hall
식당은 내일 11시부터
12시까지 문을 닫겠습니다
will be closed tomorrow from
1100 hours to 1200 hours.
곧 밤이 될 거야
핀, 어디 가는데?
It's gonna be night soon,
Finn. Where are we going?
적어도 계획은
말해줘야지
Clarke: At least tell me you have a plan
숲 속을 정처 없이
돌아다니는 건 아니잖아
and we're not just wandering
aimlessly through the woods.
내게 계획이 있어
I have a plan.
대체 이게 무슨 짓이야?
What the hell do you think you're doing?
널 살려줬다고 해서
용서 받은 건 아냐
Just because we saved you
doesn't mean you're forgiven.
알았니?
Got it?
클라크
Clarke.
뭐?
What?
꼬마 애잖아
She's just a kid.
얘는 살인자야
넌 사람을 죽였어, 샤를로트
She's a killer. You
killed someone, Charlotte.
걔 삶을 끝냈어
Ended his life.
1분 1초라도
그런 생각은 해봤니?
Did you stop to think about
that for even one second?
날 봐!
기분 내키는 대로
Look at me! You can't just kill someone
사람을 죽이면 안 돼
to make yourself feel better.
샤를로트!
Murphy: Charlotte!
클라크와 핀은
널 구해주지 못해
Clarke and Finn can't save you.
- 도망가야 해
- 응, 그것도 한 방법이지
We should run.
Yeah, that's one way to go.
내 계획이 더 좋아
I like my plan better.
들어 가
Get in.
핀, 여기가 어디야?
Finn, what is this place?
당분간은...
집이야
For now, it's home.
이런 조용한 곳을
숨기고 있었다니
I can't believe you kept this place quiet.
왜 이래, 클라크
Come on, Clarke.
- 말할 필요가 있을까?
- 물건 몇 개는 유용해
What would be the point of telling anybody?
Some of this stuff could be useful.
예를 들면?
무기도 없는데
Like what? There's no weapons.
- 음식은 90년 전에 기간이 지났어
- 그래도 다른 용도가 있잖아
All the food expired, like, 90 years ago.
Yeah, but we could repurpose.
애들과 공유하고
Share with the group.
네가 원하면
애들이랑 이것도 공유해
You can share this with
the group if you'd like.
네가 찾은 건 뭐야?
What'd you find?
글쎄...
Well...
이곳에서 조차
버티지 못한 것 같아
Looks like they never made it here.
아니, 핵폭탄이 불시에
덮쳤을 거야
No. I figure the bombs
took them by surprise.
이런 대비도
부질없는 짓이야
All this preparation. What a waste.
모르겠어
그들에겐 행운이었는지도
I don't know. Maybe they were lucky.
이곳에서 몇 년 이상은
살 수 없었을 거야
They couldn't have lived more
than a few years down here,
식량이 떨어지거나
then when they ran out of food
정신을 놓아 버리면
or lost their minds,
문을 열고선
며칠 내에 죽었을 거야
they would've opened the doors and
been dead within a few days.
그땐, 빨리 죽었겠지
Back then, maybe sooner.
어쨌든
Anyway.
저 애는 어쩌면 좋지?
Clarke: What are we gonna do about her?
머피와 맞서지 않았으면
이런 일은 없었을 텐데
If I hadn't confronted Murphy,
none of this would have happened.
일이 그렇게 커질지
네가 어찌 알아겠어?
How could you know it'd go down like that?
벨라미는 알고 있었어
Bellamy knew.
우린 지면인들을
위협적이라 생각하는데
We think the grounders are a threat.
지금은 우리 서로 죽이잖아
Now we're killing each other.
결론을 지어야 해
There have to be consequences.
사람들을 목 매달으면 안 돼
We can't just let them hang people.
맞아
No.
머피가 우릴 죽이기 전에
해결됐으면 좋겠어
Hopefully, we figure it out before Murphy
kills us for helping her.
걔는 지난 일을
잊을 타입이 아냐
He's not the forgive and forget type.
- 이걸 어떻게...
- 그 점은 염려 마
- How did you...
- Don't worry about it.
설치하는 데
얼마나 빨리 걸려?
How fast can you install it?
글쎄요
몇 시간 정도요
I don't know. A few hours, maybe.
우린 그리
시간이 많지 않아
We may not have that much time.
설치할게요
I'm on it.
선조들이 우릴 구원하기 위해
이 Ark를 만들었지만
Our ancestors built this
ark to be our salvation,
이 또한 우리의 시련입니다
but it's also our test.
우린 믿음이 있기에
견딜 수 있습니다
But we endure because we have faith.
앞으로 몇 세대가 지난
믿음의 그날이 오면
Faith that one day, generations from now,
사람들은 땅으로
되돌아 갈 겁니다
our people will return to the ground.
우리와 함께
하러 왔니?
Are you here to join us?
날 보러 온 거예요, 베라
He's here to see me, Vera.
허튼소리나 계속하세요
Go on with your mumbo-jumbo.
오늘은 당신 엄마가
생기가 넘치네요, 마커스
Your mother's inspired today, Marcus.
당신이 어린 나무였을 때가
생각나네요
I remember when you were
the tender of the tree.
참 귀여운 아이였지
You were a cute kid.
헌금을 합시다
Vera: Let's begin the offering.
왜 날 불렀어요, 나이젤?
원하는 게 뭐요?
Why did you bring me down
here, Nygel? What do you want?
당신이 원하는 거죠
It's about what you want.
줄 게 있어요
I have something for you.
구술 증거가 아니면
관심 없소
Unless is a signed
confession, I'm not interested.
애비 그리핀 의원이
관련된 거라도요?
Not even if it involves
your friend Abby Griffin?
애비 의원이 왜요?
What about Abby?
그녀와 레이븐 레예스란
여자 애가
She and a girl named Raven Reyes
압력 조절기를
내게 구해달라고 하더군요
asked me to get them a pressure regulator.
내가 하찮은 요리 기술자니
As a lowly culinary tech,
당신네 의원 중 한 명이
법을 위반하도록
I didn't feel I had a choice
when one of your fellow councillors
도와달라 했을 때
선택의 여지가 없었죠
asked me to help her break the law.
당신이 언제부터
고객을 포기했나요?
And since when en you
give up your customers?
난 고객이 없어요, 마커스
I don't have customers, Marcus.
난 Ark의 시민이고
I am a citizen of The Ark,
법 위를 군림하는 자를
믿지 않아요
and I don't believe anyone
should be above the law.
그렇죠?
Do you?
당신은 흑사병이야, 나이젤
You're a plague on this ship, Nygel.
설령 당신이 말한 게
사실이어도
And even if what you said is true,
의회의 일원에게
반박한다 해도
it's your word against
a member of the council,
사람들은 누구를
믿을까요?
and who do you think
the people will believe?
근데...내게
고마워해야 할 거요
You know... you should thank me.
애비 의원이
길을 벗어났으니
With Abby out the way,
당신의 안건은
무사히 통과될 테니
your agenda should sail right through.
무슨 말을 하는지
모르겠네요
I don't know what you're talking about.
당신도 당신 엄마처럼
거의 납득적이시네
You're almost as convincing as your mother.
언젠가는 지구가 저희를
부양할 것이고
As the earth will one day provide for us,
저희도 지구를
부양할 것입니다
so we provide for the earth.
내 생각으론
저 사람들은 폐수예요
Waste of water if you ask me.
그건 아니요
Not to them.
핀, 일어나
Finn. Finn, wake up.
없어졌어
She's gone.
- Aah! [Gasping]
- Shh. Shh.
샤를로트!
Murphy: Charlotte!
영원히 숨지 못해
You can't hide forever.
걱정 마
해치지 않을게
Don't worry. We won't hurt you.
날 놔줘요!
Let me go!
난 도와주...
I'm trying... hey, hey.
난 도와주려는 거야
I'm trying to help you.
난 오빠 여동생이 아니에요
그만 도와줘요!
I'm not your sister! Just stop helping me!
난 여깄어!
I'm over here!
우리 둘 다 죽게 하고 싶어?
Are you trying to get us both killed?
그냥 가세요
나만 원하잖아요
Just go, ok? I'm the one they want.
좋아, 샤를로트
내 말 잘 들어
Ok, Charlotte, listen to me.
난 널 버리지 않아`
I won't leave you.
제발, 벨라미 오빠
Please, Bellamy.
[Gasping]
머피! 난 여깄어!
Aah! Murphy! I'm over here!
어서 나와, 샤를로트!
나오라고!
Come on out, Charlotte! Come on out.
다른 애들도 있어
Someone else was here.
- 안 돼! 머피!
- 머피가 잡았어
- Charlotte: No, no! Murphy!
- Murphy has her.
다음엔 제가 박사님 수술실에서
서성거리면 어떨까요?
Abby, how about I pace
in the operating room
next time you're working?
[Beeping]
박사님, 클리닉에서
모르핀을 가져갔나요?
Abby, did you take
morphine from the clinic?
이미 재고 조사를 했어?
They inventoried already?
아뇨, 케인이 방금 와서
No. Kane was just here.
He's on his way to Mecha
수리공과 박사님을
체포하러 오고 있어요
to arrest both of you right now.
나이젤에게 모르핀을 줬죠?
You gave Nygel morphine?
날 배신했어
She turned me in.
- 얼마나 더 걸려?
- 20분요
How much longer?
20 minutes.
5분 후에 도착할 거야
They're gonna be here in 5.
[Sigh] No matter what happens,
무슨 일이 있더라도
발사해
you launch that pod.
내 말 알겠지?
Do you understand?
박사님 없인 안 가요
I'm not going without you.
한 명만이 땅을
밟을 수 있어, 레이븐
Only one of us needs to
get to the ground, Raven.
아이들을 찾는 순간
무선으로 연락해
The second you find those kids,
you radio back.
네가 못 하면
무고한 300명이 죽어
300 innocent people will die if you don't.
그들이 박사님을
처형할 거예요
Abby, they'll float you.
처형하라고 해
Then they'll float me.
클라크에게
사랑한다고 전해 줘
Tell Clarke I love her.
샤를로트!
- Charlotte: Aah!
- Murphy: Charlotte!
날 내려놔요!
Put me down!
샤를로트!
Murphy: Charlotte!
젠장!
Bellamy: Damn it.
벨라미!
Bellamy!
우리와 다 상대할 순 없어
포기해
You cannot fight all of us. Give her up.
그래도, 몇 명은
상대할 수는 있어
Maybe not, but I guarantee
I'll take a few of you with me.
벨라미, 그만 해!
Clarke: Bellamy! Stop!
이건 도를 넘었어
This has gone too far.
다들 진정해
Just calm down.
나중에 얘기해
We'll talk about this.
네 말을 듣는 게
진절머리가 나
I'm sick of listening to you talk.
- 놔 줘
- 목을 그어버리겠어
- Let her go.
- I will slit her throat.
안 돼요, 제발
해치지 마세요
No, please. Please don't hurt her.
해치지 말라고?
Murphy: Don't hurt her?
좋아, 거래를 하지
Ok, I'll make you a deal.
네가 지금 내게 오면
얘를 놔줄게
You come with me right now,
I will let her go.
그러지 마, 샤를로트
Don't do it, Charlotte.
그러지 마, 샤를로트!
Clarke: Don't do it, Charlotte!
놔요! 갈 거예요!
No! No, I have to!
머피, 이럴 일이
일어나선 안 돼
Man: Murphy, this is not happening.
더이상 사람들이 다치게
내버려 둘 순 없어요
I can't let any of you get hurt anymore.
내가 한 짓 때문에
싸우지 마세요
Not because of me. Not after what I did.
샤를로트!
Charlotte!
안 돼!
No!
안 돼, 안 돼
안 돼!
No, no, no! No!
[Gasp]
벨라미
Bellamy.
[Bellamy screams]
벨라미
Bellamy.
벨라미, 그만해!
그러다 죽겠어!
Bellamy, stop! You'll kill him!
날 내버려 둬!
저 놈은 죽어도 싸!
Get off me! Uhh! He deserves to die.
안 돼, 우린 생사를
결정짓지 못해!
No! We don't decide who lives and dies.
지구에선 안 돼
Not down here.
신이시여, 사람들이 결정할
권리가 있다고 하시면...
So help me God, if you say the people
have a right to decide...
안 돼
내가 전에 잘못했어
No, I was wrong before, ok?
네 말이 맞았어
You were right.
때론 사람들에게 진실을
말하는 것도 위험해
Sometimes it's dangerous
to tell people the truth.
하지만 이곳에서
살아 남을려면
But if we're gonna survive down here,
우리가 원하는 대로
살아 갈 수는 없어
we can't just live by
whatever the hell we want.
우린 규칙이 필요해
We need rules.
그럼 누가 규칙을
만들 건데, 네가?
And who makes those rules, huh? You?
당분간은 우리가
규칙을 만들면 되잖아?
For now, we make the rules. Ok?
그래서 뭐?
쟤를 데려가서
So, what, then? We just take him back
아무 일 없었던 듯이
지내자고?
and pretend like it never happened?
아니!
No!
추방해야지
We banish him.
일어 나
Get up.
벨라미! 그만 해!
Bellamy! Stop!
캠프 근처에서 잡히면
여기로 다시 올 줄 알아
If I ever catch you near camp,
we'll be back here.
알았어?
Understand?
너희 4명도
Bellamy: As for the four of you,
날 다시 따를 건지
you can come back and follow me,
아님 쟤를 따라
죽을 건지
or go off with him to die.
너희들이 선택해
Your choice.
제발!
Come on, come on!
안 돼!
No!
젠장!
Damn it!
불량 부품을 줬어
She gave us a bad part.
당신 말야...
타당한 해명이 있어야 할 거야
I'm hoping...
there's a logical explanation for all this.
내 딸
My daughter.
알아, 유감이야
I know. I'm sorry.
승산이 없다는 거
잘 알잖아
We all knew it was a long shot.
난 여전히 믿어요
I still believe.
압력 조절기는
무슨 목적이야, 애비?
What's the pressure regulator for, Abby?
박테리아는 없잖아
안 그래?
There's no bacteria, is there?
세균에 감염된
수리공...
Your infected mechanic...
레이븐 레예스
Raven Reyes.
그녀는 뭘 하고 있지?
What's she up to?
그 100명 중에 핀 콜린스가
그녀의 남자 친구란 걸...
Did you know that her
boyfriend Finn Collins...
알고 있었지?
was one of the hundred?
당신의 집착 때문에...
Your obsession...
그녀도 처형을
당할 거야
is now gonna get her floated, too.
[Beeping]
당신이 하는 일을
실토하지 않으면...
If you don't tell me what you're up to...
그녀를 살릴 수 없어
I won't be able to save her.
당신은 지금도
이해를 못해요
You still don't understand.
난 모두를 살리려는 거예요
I'm trying to save all of us.
체포해
Arrest her.
- 레이븐 레예스를 계속 찾아 봐
- 네
Continue to search for Raven Reyes.
Sir.
[Airlock door opens]
[Beeping]
방금 뭐였지?
Man: What was that?
의원님, 발사됐습니다
Sir, a pod launched.
애비, 뭔 짓을 한 거야?
Abby... what have you done?
우린 진실을 알아야죠
We have to know the truth.
그래서 우린 걔를
추방하기로...
That's why we've decided to banish...
불만 있는 사람은 없지?
Man: Anybody got a problem with that?
[Music]
[Beeping]
- 얘기는 할 수 있는 거지?
- 아니, 모스 부호로만
Will we be able to talk to them?
No. More like morse code.
네가 주인역 할래?
You want to do the honors?
바로 거기
그 포트
That port right there.
[Beeping]
[Music]
[Crackling] Oh!
Oh! Uhh!
Ooh.
[Alarm blaring]
대체 이게...?
What the hell?
어떻게 됐어?
What happened?
작동이 안 됐어
It didn't work.
모든 팔찌가 고장난 것 같아
I think we fried all the wristbands.
스스로 위험을 감수하고
가만히 있을래
Sit there at your own risk.
난 저주 받은 것 같아
I think I might be cursed.
그럼 날 모험가라 불러
Then call me a risk taker.
제스퍼, 넌 저주 받지 않았어
And Jasper, you're not cursed.
그럼 난 행운아네
I'm lucky then.
아니, 용감해
No. Brave.
용감해?
Brave? [Sniffles]
내 얼굴이 반쪽이 되거나
For getting my face bashed in
Ark에 연락할 기회를
날려버렸는데?
or for ruining any
chance to contact The Ark?
아니, 불량배에게
대항했고
No, for standing up to a bully
모두를 도우려고 했잖아
and trying to help everyone.
응, 근데 실패했어
두 번 모두
Yeah. And failing. Both times.
앞으로 나서는 사람은
보질 못했어, 응?
I didn't see anyone else step up. Did you?
난 결과가 어떻든
상관 안 해
And I don't care how things turned out.
넌 용감했잖아
You were brave to try.
용감하면 늘 보상을 받아
And bravery is always rewarded.
핀!
Finn!
핀, 그만 해!
진정해!
Finn, stop it! Calm down!
우리가 그들을 죽인 거야!
모르겠냐고?
We're dead to them! Don't you get that?
- 아니, 아직은 희망이 있어
- 네가 믿지 않을 뿐이지
No, there's still hope.
Even you don't believe that.
끝났어, 클라크
It's over, Clarke.
그들은 죽게 될 거야
우리만 남기고
They're gonna die up
there, and we're alone.
넌 혼자가 아냐
You're not alone.
[Music]
- synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.addic7ed.com -
우리말 옮긴이 : BaeZZi
- synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.addic7ed.com -